free-css.com 2019-04-23

# Free CSS | Privacy Policy

Data privacy is a major concern that Free CSS takes seriously, this page is dedicated to inform our users of our conformance to the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), in regard to the type, scope and purpose of collecting and the use of personal data by Free CSS.com ("Free CSS", "we", "us" or "our").

Free CSS.com can be used without the provision of personal information. If and when personal data is required when using the Free CSS website (e.g name, address, email or phone number etc.) the provision of personal data is carried out on a voluntary basis and is the sole decision of the user to submit their persoanl data.

Any personal data that is sent to us via the Free CSS website (via forms or direct email), is in no means disclosed to third parties without explicit consent from the person who sent us the information. If legally bound to, we may disclose information you have provided to law enforcement officials or government agencies.

Your data privacy is taken seriously by us, all information that you may provide is treated confidentially and in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation.

**Handling of Personal Data**

Free CSS only uses your data if the usage is permitted by law and or if you have consented to the use of your personal data. When you actively submit your personal data vie email or via a form found in our website, you automatically consent to Free CSS using your data to process your enquiry.

Definition of Personal information: any and all data that can be used to identify a natural person and can be used to find you, such as your full name, email address and phone number(s) you provide.

**Handling of Contact Information**

If for any reason you need to contact us via any of the contact preferences that can be found in our website, the information you send us will be stored on a short-term basis so we can answer your enquiry.

Without your consent, all of the data you have submitted to us will not be given to third parties, with the exception, that we may disclose information about you to governmental or law enforcement officials, when and if we are legally bound to do so.

**User Rights**

You have the right of information, correction and deletion of personal data that you have sent us. You are entitled to receive free information about the personal data we have stored about you.

If your request does not conflict with any laws Free CSS has to abide to, you are entitled to ask us to:

  * correct / update your information
  * block / restrict your information
  * delete your information

If you would like further information or want us to carry out any of the above, please feel free to contact us.

**Server Logs**

Our hosting provider collects website access data and saves the data in "server log files", the following (known) data is written to the log files:

  * IP address
  * Browser type
  * Operating system
  * Server access on/when
  * Amount of data sent
  * Referrer URL
  * Computer host name

The data is used for statistical purposes only, but, Free CSS reserves the right in retrospective effect to check server log files should evidence be available that indicates illegal / unlawful use of the Free CSS website.

Our provider stores Log Files for a maximum of 9 weeks, after this time the files are permanently deleted from the server.

IP addresses that are in the log files are anonymised by our provider after a period of 7 days, this is to our knowledge, automated. The anonymisation ensures the process of identifying a natural person via the IP address is not possible.

**Social Media Links**

We have multiple links in our website to a variety of social media platforms. These links are ther for the end-user to use to add pages they like to their social media platform of choice.

All of the links are controlled by us and none of them send personal data when clicked. The social media platforms that we link to probably use user tracking, which will let them know where you have come from after landing on their website, the data that is collected by the social media platform has nothing to do with us and we can not prevent it.

**Website Cookies**

Please view our cookies policy, which can be found here.

**Google Analytics Tracking**

We use "Google Analytics", which is a service provided by Google Inc. (1600 Amphitheater Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA) to analyse user behaviour whilst on our website, Google Analytics sets "cookies", which are stored on your computer or smart device when you visit this website.

Information collected by Google Analytics is sent to and stored on servers based in the USA.

We make use of Googles "IP anonymization" method. Basically, the users IP address is modified (to our knowledge, only users within the EU and the EEA). This technique makes sure that the identification of a natural person using the IP address is not possible.

As a user of our site, you have the choice to prevent cookies being stored on your device by simply changing the settings in your browser. You may not be able to access all of the features of our website without any restriction when configuring your browser to disallow cookies.

To stop Google Analytics from tracking your behaviour on our website click this link to opt-out and Analytics will be stopped.

This feature is device dependant, which means the cookie that is set is a per-device cookie, so the opt-out must be carried out on all the devices you use to view our website with.

There is also the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) that you can use to do the same.

Other resources:

  * [Google Analytics security and privacy principles - Safeguarding your data](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245)

**Google reCAPTCHA**

Although this feature is not currently setup / used in our website, it is possible that we will use it in the future.

reCAPTCHA is a service provided by Google Inc., reCAPTCHA is a service used to help protect forms from being submitted maliciously.

The service can be found in contact forms in our website and it is primarily used to distinguish between a real person and a bot, to help prevent our forms from being abused.

reCAPTCHA collects data, including your IP address and other browser information the service requires, the collected data is sent to and used by Google.

If you are viewing our website from within the EU or an EEA area, your IP address gets anonymised. In some rare occasions your IP could be sent to a Google server in the USA and anonymised there.

Google uses the data it collects to evaluate the use of its service for the owner of the website. The IP address collected by reCAPTCHA shall not be included in other data sets from other services provided by Google. The reCAPTCHA service and its collection of data is regulated by Google Inc., read their [privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en).

By using forms which use reCAPTCHA in our website, you agree to Google using the data collected in the manner of and for the purpose described in this policy.

**Links to External Websites**

Our website contains links to external websites that are unassociated with privacy laws we are regulated by.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to or regulate linked external websites, we are not responsible nor can we be held responsible for the content found on external websites or how these sites are managed.

**Online Security**

The internet is not secure, as such, we make as many technical and organisational precautions as possible to assist in helping prevent alteration, loss or illegal misuse of data that has been given to us.

Transmitting data over the internet is not fail-safe, as such, it can be vulnerable, the access of data from criminals can not be completely ruled-out and is not guaranteed.

We can not guarantee that data you send us via the internet won't be altered, lost or illegaly misused by criminals, but, we do our utmost to prevent it from happening.

**Policy Updates**

Policy updates will only be posted in this page.

If changes made to our policy effect user information we will contact users requesting permission to continue to use the information or and when requested delete, update or restrict the use of said data.

The use of our website after policy changes have been completed indicate your agreement to all changes made.

**Policy Agreement**

If for any reason you do not agree with our policy, you are asked to not use our website. If you stay on our website and use its services, you automatically agree to the Free CSS Privacy Policy.

By using the Free CSS website, you consent to us collecting contact and or personal information as well as statistical user information and grant us permission to make use of the information as described in this policy.

**Updates**

Last update: 01.06.2018
